<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Retrieval Market in Filecoin on Filecoin Spec</title>
    <link>/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Retrieval Market in Filecoin on Filecoin Spec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Client</title>
      <link>/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/retrieval_client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/retrieval_client/</guid>
      <description>Client Dependencies The Retrieval Client Depends On The Following Dependencies
 Host: A libp2p host (set setup the libp2p protocols) Filecoin Node: A node implementation to query the chain for pieces and to setup and manage payment channels BlockStore: Same as one used by data transfer module Data Transfer: V1 only &amp;ndash;Module used for transferring payload. Writes to the blockstore.  API import abi &amp;#34;github.com/filecoin-project/specs-actors/actors/abi&amp;#34; import addr &amp;#34;github.com/filecoin-project/go-address&amp;#34; import peer &amp;#34;github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Peer Resolver</title>
      <link>/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/retrieval_peer_resolver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/retrieval_peer_resolver/</guid>
      <description>The peer resolver is a content routing interface to discover retrieval miners that have a given Piece.
It can be backed by both a local store of previous storage deals or by querying the chain.
import abi &amp;#34;github.com/filecoin-project/specs-actors/actors/abi&amp;#34; type RetrievalPeerResolver struct { GetPeers(PieceCID abi.PieceCID) [RetrievalPeer] }  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Protocols</title>
      <link>/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/retrieval_protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/retrieval_protocols/</guid>
      <description>The retrieval market will initially be implemented as two libp2p services.
 Name: Query Protocol Protocol ID V0: /fil/&amp;lt;network-name&amp;gt;/retrieval/qry/0.0.1 Protocol ID V1: /fil/&amp;lt;network-name&amp;gt;/retrieval/qry/1.0.0  Request: CBOR Encoded RetrievalQuery Data Structure Response: CBOR Encoded RetrievalQueryResponse Data Structure
 Name: Retrieval Protocol Protocol ID V0: /fil/&amp;lt;network-name&amp;gt;/retrieval/0.0.1  V0: Request: CBOR Encoded RetrievalDealProposal Data Structure Response: CBOR Encoded RetrievalDealResponse Data Structure &amp;ndash; Following Request: CBOR Encoded RetrievalPayment Data Structure Response: CBOR Encoded RetrievalDealResponse Data Structure w/ Blocks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Provider (Miner)</title>
      <link>/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/retrieval_provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/systems/filecoin_markets/retrieval_market/retrieval_provider/</guid>
      <description>Provider Dependencies The Retrieval Provider Depends On The Following Dependencies
 Host: A libp2p host (set setup the libp2p protocols) Filecoin Node: A node implementation to query the chain for pieces and to setup and manage payment channels StorageMining Subsystem: For unsealing sectors BlockStore: Same as one used by data transfer module Data Transfer: V1 only &amp;ndash; Module used for transferring payload. Reads from the blockstore.  API import abi &amp;#34;github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>