<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain Components on Filecoin Spec</title>
    <link>/docs/systems/filecoin_blockchain/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchain Components on Filecoin Spec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/systems/filecoin_blockchain/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Block Producer</title>
      <link>/docs/systems/filecoin_blockchain/blockchain/block_producer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/systems/filecoin_blockchain/blockchain/block_producer/</guid>
      <description>Mining Blocks Having registered as a miner, it&amp;rsquo;s time to start making and checking tickets. At this point, the miner should already be running chain validation, which includes keeping track of the latest Tipsets seen on the network.
For additional details around how consensus works in Filecoin, see the expected consensus spec. For the purposes of this section, there is a consensus protocol (Expected Consensus) that guarantees a fair process for determining what blocks have been generated in a round, whether a miner should mine a block themselves, and some rules pertaining to how &amp;ldquo;Tickets&amp;rdquo; should be validated during block validation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block Syncer</title>
      <link>/docs/systems/filecoin_blockchain/blockchain/block_syncer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/systems/filecoin_blockchain/blockchain/block_syncer/</guid>
      <description>In order to ensure they are always on the correct latest state of the blockchain, a Filecoin node must continuously monitor and propagate blocks on the network.
When a node receives blocks, it must also validate them. Validation is split into two stages, syntactic and semantic. The syntactic stage may be validated without reference to additional data, the semantic stage requires access to the chain which the block extends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain Manager</title>
      <link>/docs/systems/filecoin_blockchain/blockchain/chain_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/systems/filecoin_blockchain/blockchain/chain_manager/</guid>
      <description>The Chain Manager is a central component in the blockchain system. It tracks and updates competing subchains received by a given node in order to select the appropriate blockchain head: the latest block of the heaviest subchain it is aware of in the system.
In so doing, the chain manager is the central subsystem that handles bookkeeping for numerous other systems in a Filecoin node and exposes convenience methods for use by those systems, enabling systems to sample randomness from the chain for instance, or to see which block has been finalized most recently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>