<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proof-of-Spacetime on Filecoin Spec</title>
    <link>/docs/algorithms/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proof-of-Spacetime on Filecoin Spec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/algorithms/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Election PoSt</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/post/election_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/post/election_post/</guid>
      <description>This document describes Election-PoSt, the Proof-of-Spacetime used in Filecoin.
At a high-level it marries ElectionPoSt with a SurprisePoSt fallback:
 By coupling leader election and PoSt, ElectionPoSt ensures that miners must do the work to prove their sectors at every round in order to earn block rewards. Small miners may not win on a regular basis however, SurprisePoSt thus comes in as a lower-bound to how often miners must PoSt and helps ensure the Power Table does not grow stale for its long-tail of smaller miners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PoSt Parameters</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/post/proof_of_spacetime_parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/post/proof_of_spacetime_parameters/</guid>
      <description>This section describes parameters for Rational-PoSt, the Proof-of-Spacetime used in Filecoin.
   Parameter Type Value Description   POST-CHALLENGE-BLOCKS BLOCKS 480 The time offset before which the actual work of generating the PoSt cannot be started. This is some delta before the end of the Proving Period, and as such less than a single Proving Period.   POST-CHALLENGE-HOURS HOURS 2 PoSt challenge time (see POST_CHALLENGE_BLOCKS).   POST-PROVING-PERIOD BLOCKS 5760 The time interval in which a PoSt has to be submitted    TODO: The above values are tentative and need both backing from research as well as detailed reasoning why we picked them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>