<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proof-of-Spacetime on Filecoin Spec</title>
    <link>/docs/algorithms/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proof-of-Spacetime on Filecoin Spec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/algorithms/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Election PoSt</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/post/election_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/post/election_post/</guid>
      <description>This document describes Election-PoSt, the Proof-of-Spacetime used in Filecoin.
High Level API Election PoSt couples the PoSt process with block production, meaning that in order to produce a block, the miner must produce a valid PoSt proof (snark output). Specifically, a subset of non-faulted sectors the miner is storing (i.e. eligible sectors) allows them to attempt a leader election using a PartialTicket any of which could yield a valid ChallengeTicket for leader election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PoSt Parameters</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/post/proof_of_spacetime_parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/post/proof_of_spacetime_parameters/</guid>
      <description>This section describes parameters for Rational-PoSt, the Proof-of-Spacetime used in Filecoin.
   Parameter Type Value Description     POST-CHALLENGE-BLOCKS BLOCKS 480 The time offset before which the actual work of generating the PoSt cannot be started. This is some delta before the end of the Proving Period, and as such less than a single Proving Period.   POST-CHALLENGE-HOURS HOURS 2 PoSt challenge time (see POST_CHALLENGE_BLOCKS).   POST-PROVING-PERIOD BLOCKS 5760 The time interval in which a PoSt has to be submitted    TODO: The above values are tentative and need both backing from research as well as detailed reasoning why we picked them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PoSt Parameters</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/post/proof_of_spacetime_parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/post/proof_of_spacetime_parameters/</guid>
      <description>This section describes parameters for Rational-PoSt, the Proof-of-Spacetime used in Filecoin. (asdf:load-system :orient) (in-package orient.lang)  #&amp;lt;PACKAGE &amp;#34;ORIENT.LANG&amp;#34;&amp;gt;  (defparameter *filecoin* (get-system &amp;#34;../../orient/filecoin.orient&amp;#34;)) (defparameter *input* (interface:get-json-relation-list &amp;#34;../../orient/params.json&amp;#34;)) (defparameter *multi-input* (interface:get-json-relation-list &amp;#34;../../orient/multi-params.json&amp;#34;))  *MULTI-INPUT*  (let ((result-tuple (extract (ask *filecoin* &amp;#39;(post-challenge-blocks post-challenge-hours post-proving-period) *input*)))) (org-present-tuple result-tuple *filecoin*))     Parameter Type Value Description   POST-CHALLENGE-BLOCKS BLOCKS 480 The time offset before which the actual work of generating the PoSt cannot be started.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>