<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cryptographic Primitives on Filecoin Spec</title>
    <link>/docs/algorithms/crypto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cryptographic Primitives on Filecoin Spec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/algorithms/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Randomness</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/crypto/randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/crypto/randomness/</guid>
      <description>Randomness is used throughout the protocol in order to generate values and extend the blockchain. Random values are drawn from the Ticket Chain and appropriately formatted for usage. We describe this formatting below.
Encoding On-chain data for randomness Any randomness derived from on-chain values uses the following encodings to represent these values as bytes:
 Bytes: Bytes Ints: Big-endian uint64 representation Strings: ASCII Objects: Their specified Serialization, currently CBOR-based serialization defined on algebraic datatypes  Domain Separation Tags For Signatures as well as Verifiable Random Function usage in the protocol, we define Domain Separation Tags with which we prepend random inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signatures</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/crypto/signatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/crypto/signatures/</guid>
      <description>Signatures are cryptographic functions that attest to the origin of a particular message. In the context of Filecoin, signatures are used to send and receive messages with the assurance that each message was generated by a specific entity. In other words, it is infeasible for an entity i to generate a signed message that appears to have been generated by j, with j != i.
Filecoin uses signatures to associate an action to a given party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verifiable Random Function</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/crypto/vrf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/crypto/vrf/</guid>
      <description>Filecoin uses the notion of a Verifiable Random Function (VRF). A VRF uses a private key to produce a digest of an arbitrary message such that the output is unique per signer and per message. Any third party in possession of the corresponding public key, the message and the VRF output can verify if the digest has been computed correctly and from the correct signer. Using a VRF in the ticket generation process allows anyone to verify if a block comes from an eligible block producer (see Ticket Generation for more details).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>