<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithms on Filecoin Spec</title>
    <link>/docs/algorithms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithms on Filecoin Spec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/algorithms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Block Reception</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/block_reception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/block_reception/</guid>
      <description>func (g *BlockValidationGraph_I) ConsiderBlock(block Block) { panic(&amp;ldquo;TODO&amp;rdquo;) // g.UnconnectedBlocks.AddBlock(block) // g.tryConnectBlockToFringe(block) }
func (g *BlockValidationGraph_I) tryConnectBlockToFringe(block Block) { panic(&amp;ldquo;TODO&amp;rdquo;)
// try to connect the block, and then try connecting its descendents. // // this algorithm should be breadth-first because we need to process the fringe // in order. Depth-first search may consider blocks whose parents are still // yet to be added // blocks := Queue &amp;lt; Block &amp;gt; // blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BlockSync</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/block_sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/block_sync/</guid>
      <description>Name: Block Sync Protocol ID: /fil/sync/blk/0.0.1  The blocksync protocol is a small protocol that allows Filecoin nodes to request ranges of blocks from each other. It is a simple request/response protocol.
The request requests a chain of a given length by the hash of its highest block. The Options allow the requester to specify whether or not blocks and messages to be included.
The response contains the requested chain in reverse iteration order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GossipSub</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/gossip_sub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/gossip_sub/</guid>
      <description>Messages and block headers along side the message references are propagated using the gossipsub libp2p pubsub router. Every full node must implement and run that protocol. All pubsub messages are authenticated and must be syntactically validated before being propagated further.
Further more, every full node must implement and offer the bitswap protocol and provide all Cid Referenced objects, it knows of, through it. This allows any node to fetch missing pieces (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Payment Channels</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/payment_channels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/payment_channels/</guid>
      <description>Payment Channels In order for the Filecoin Markets to work in a timely manner, we need to be able to have off-chain payments. This is a solved problem (at least, for our purposes in v0). Payment channels have been implemented and used in bitcoin, ethereum and many other networks.
The basic premise is this: User A wants to be able to send many small payments to user B. So user A locks up money in a contract that says &amp;ldquo;this money will only go to user B, and the unclaimed amount will be returned to user A after a set time period&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>