<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>System Decomposition on Filecoin Spec</title>
    <link>/docs/intro/system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System Decomposition on Filecoin Spec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/intro/system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Systems</title>
      <link>/docs/intro/system/impl_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/intro/system/impl_systems/</guid>
      <description>System Requirements In order to make it easier to decouple functionality into systems, the Filecoin Protocol assumes a set of functionality available to all systems. This functionality can be achieved by implementations in a variety of ways, and should take the guidance here as a recommendation (SHOULD).
All Systems, as defined in this document, require the following:
 Repository:  Local IpldStore. Some amount of persistent local storage for data structures (small structured objects).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Systems? How do they work?</title>
      <link>/docs/intro/system/why_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/intro/system/why_systems/</guid>
      <description>Filecoin decouples and modularizes functionality into loosely-joined systems. Each system adds significant functionality, usually to achieve a set of important and tightly related goals.
For example, the Blockchain System provides structures like Block, Tipset, and Chain, and provides functionality like Block Sync, Block Propagation, Block Validation, Chain Selection, and Chain Access. This is separated from the Files, Pieces, Piece Preparation, and Data Transfer. Both of these systems are separated from the Markets, which provide Orders, Deals, Market Visibility, and Deal Settlement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>