<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proof-of-Replication on Filecoin Spec</title>
    <link>/docs/algorithms/porep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proof-of-Replication on Filecoin Spec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/algorithms/porep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stacked DRG - Offline PoRep Circuit Spec</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/porep/stacked_drg_circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/porep/stacked_drg_circuit/</guid>
      <description>Stacked DRG Overview Stacked DRG PoRep is based on layering DRG graphs LAYERS times. The data represented in each DRG layer is a labeling based on previously labeled nodes. The final labeled layer is the SDR key, and the &amp;lsquo;final layer&amp;rsquo; of replication the replica, an encoding of the original data using the generated key.
 ReplicaId is a unique replica identifier (see the Filecoin Proofs spec for details). CommD is the Merkle tree root hash of the input data to the first layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stacked DRG PoRep</title>
      <link>/docs/algorithms/porep/stacked_drg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/algorithms/porep/stacked_drg/</guid>
      <description>This section describes Stacked DRG PoRep (SDR), the specific Proof-of-Replication (PoRep) used in Filecoin. In this construction, the prover encodes the original data into a replica and commits to it. An offline PoRep proves that the commitment to the replica is a valid commitment of the encoded original data.
SDR has been presented by Ben Fisch at EUROCRYPT19.
Introduction Background on Proof-of-Replication Proof-of-Replication enables a prover P to convince a verifier V that P is storing a replica R, a physically independent copy of some data D, unique to P.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>